<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Ds Development on Bayesian Politics</title>
    <link>/tags/ds-development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Ds Development on Bayesian Politics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-US</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/tags/ds-development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we as Data Scientists care about how computers communicate?</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10/why-do-we-as-data-scientists-care-about-how-computers-communicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10/why-do-we-as-data-scientists-care-about-how-computers-communicate/</guid>
      <description>You turn on your computer, and connect to the WiFi. You open your browser and remember that you have to pay your credit card. You search for the bank&amp;rsquo;s name and click the first link you see, because the first one is always the correct one. You submit the credit card information and then get an email confirming your payment. But, how are you sure you submitted your information in the bank&amp;rsquo;s page? Or, how are you sure no one gained access to it?
When you turned on your computer, connected to the WiFi, opened the browser and started searching, your computer started sending little pieces of information in what are called packets. This packets contain the message or information you want to send, but also who sent it and where it is going. We identify the computers communicating using primarily IP Addresses, which are numbers that specify your internet address. However, how this computers communicate, validate each other, and understand the messages varies greatly by the network protocol you are using.
But, why do we as Data Scientists care about how computers communicate? Over the last years there has been a surge in the amount and complexity of data we analyze.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>