<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Bayesian Politics</title>
    <link>/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Bayesian Politics</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-CA</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Dec 2018 22:31:21 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dancing the K-Means Dance</title>
      <link>/blog/2019-05/dancing-the-k-means-dance/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2019-05/dancing-the-k-means-dance/</guid>
      <description>Dancing can be traced back to the origins of almost every society in the world. It is a way to communicate ideas and feelings in a free manner. [I would add something here about how dance is a simple, memorable and effective way to communicate? Maybe give an example of children&amp;rsquo;s dance songs in an educational/story telling context?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feminicides in Latin America and the Caribbean</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11/feminicides-in-latin-america-and-the-caribbean/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11/feminicides-in-latin-america-and-the-caribbean/</guid>
      <description>Context According to statistics from the Puerto Rico Police Department, reported this week in a newspaper from Puerto Rico, there&amp;rsquo;s been 21 women killed by their partners or ex-partners in 2018 in the island. [1] Feminist collectives have expressed that the total feminicide count is around 40 women. However, how do we define feminicide?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Feminicidios en Latino América y el Caribe</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11/feminicidios-en-latino-am%C3%A9rica-y-el-caribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11/feminicidios-en-latino-am%C3%A9rica-y-el-caribe/</guid>
      <description>El blog post completo se encuentra aqui: https://www.bayesianpolitik.me/feminicidesLATAM/feminicides_es Debido a limitaciones con el software las graficas y las tablas que van adjuntas al texto solo estan disponibles en el enlace de arriba. Por favor lea el post ahi. La imagen en la parte superior es del libro de Eduardo Galeano &amp;lsquo;Las Venas Abiertas de América Latina&amp;rsquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Datos Históricos de las Elecciones en Puerto Rico</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11/datos-hist%C3%B3ricos-de-las-elecciones-en-puerto-rico/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11/datos-hist%C3%B3ricos-de-las-elecciones-en-puerto-rico/</guid>
      <description>Contexto Descargue todos los datos catalogados como históricos en la página de la Comisión Estatal de Elecciones de Puerto Rico para hacerlos accesible en un formato que pueda ser combinado con datos del Censo, así como otros indicadores socio-económicos para entender mejor los patrones políticos en Puerto Rico. En el próximo mes estare añadiendo los datos de las elecciones de 2004, 2008, 2012, y 2016 pero con mayor detalle espacial que por municipios.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Historical Data on Puerto Rico Elections</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-11/historical-data-on-puerto-rico-elections/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-11/historical-data-on-puerto-rico-elections/</guid>
      <description>Context I scraped all the historical data from the Puerto Rico&amp;rsquo;s Electoral Commission webpage to make it accesible in a way that can be combined with Census data, as well as other socio-economic indicators to better explain political patterns in Puerto Rico. In the next month I will add as well the elections of 2004, 2008, 2012, 2016, but with a more granual level than municipalities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How was mortality distributed through Puerto Rico after Hurricane Maria?</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10/how-was-mortality-distributed-through-puerto-rico-after-hurricane-maria/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10/how-was-mortality-distributed-through-puerto-rico-after-hurricane-maria/</guid>
      <description>Context  Hurricane Maria struck Puerto Rico the 20th of September of 2017 at 6:15 a.m. entering through the municipality of Yabucoa as a Category 4 hurricane. According to the governments of Puerto Rico and the U.S. Virgin islands, the cost of the damage is estimated in $102 billion USD1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why do we as Data Scientists care about how computers communicate?</title>
      <link>/blog/2018-10/why-do-we-as-data-scientists-care-about-how-computers-communicate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/blog/2018-10/why-do-we-as-data-scientists-care-about-how-computers-communicate/</guid>
      <description>You turn on your computer, and connect to the WiFi. You open your browser and remember that you have to pay your credit card. You search for the bank&amp;rsquo;s name and click the first link you see, because the first one is always the correct one. You submit the credit card information and then get an email confirming your payment.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>